welcome to saturday roundtable
where we tell you about our projects
what we've been up to and what we
are up to in the next little while what
we could maybe use upon
who would like to start
i can go uh so
my i'm working on several projects right
now
the long-term one is reason score it
helps with mass agreement
so helps people work through challenging
conversations at society-wide scale
i have not worked on that in the last
couple weeks although
some of the other projects i'm working
on that i'll mention
can use it as a small part of it it's
really kind of a
feature of other sites to add
kind of the ability for people to handle
disputes in communities and stuff like
that
so one of the other projects is a
crowdsourced rating system for
uh products communities
and politicians etc etc etc anything
else you'd ever want to have the crowd
rate and
also rating features so if you have a
politician do they
have the same values that you do and
then
you as a user can go in um say the
features
or attributes that you want to you can
weigh all the different attributes and
say what's important to you
and then the system would kind of match
you up and show you
how everyone or every system or every
product
rates based upon your values
so that's the um i've written up
a document about that and did some extra
wording
so every time i mention it i get
contacted by someone else
i guess i'm going in too long of an
update but
that's you know that's the other project
uh there's another one
who's who works with a lot of different
community groups and they're small
groups
so they want a way to match people up to
groups and you know some groups are
full of extroverts that want to do a lot
of chatting some people want to get
right down to business so
having the ability to find a group that
matches your
your desires would be helpful and so
that tool can be used for that as well
uh and then working with adriel
eventually on
some sort of uh sharepoint not
sharepoint
what's the salesforce plugins and i
found out also
adalo a no code
application builder is they have a new
marketplace for plugins
so that'd be interesting because it's an
evolving space they don't have it yet
where you can charge for your plugins
they're just free but they're that's in
the works for them to set up a
billing platform and stuff so it's kind
of like the wordpress
marketplace um but it's in a new new and
emerging space which is often where um
some money gets made so those are the
projects
i can think of that's where i'm at
cool i can go next uh so my project
is wikilection it is a uh
platform to fight misinformation in
politics science and news
uh i've been working with someone else
who very well might be showing up in the
next
10 to 20 minutes uh named matush
we have a prototype online uh i'm hoping
to get the new version of the prototype
this weekend um where we will be adding
the legislation tracker
and then the next part is going to be
tracking the actual content
um which for now we'll just be tracking
the content of how we knew about the
legislation so it won't be terribly
interesting
but uh sort of hopefully in the next two
or three
feature releases things will start to
come together and it'll actually start
to sort of
make sense and be useful um but as it is
right now it's not terribly useful it's
just
got pick data and not
really enough features actually do do
anything um
but it's actually coming along quite
quite nicely so
and then in the near future uh
it'll be sort of cloned and a
different version of it will be online
under the name conferati
which will specialize in tracking
information about organizations
um but
i just muted you daniel because i think
you had adroll's twice in the
background ah welcome daniel my project
is solution raising is my
biggest project although i start fires
and start new projects all the time
uh solution raising is an hour-long
conversation where we generate
ideas that we can implement now if we
had ten thousand people and a hundred
thousand dollars
the last week i signed up for instagram
i've been on there
not gaining followers between live
videos and involved with the ntmlm
community on there and finding new ways
i've been stalking celebrities and
suggesting they have solution raisings
i'm like if the mlm people can do it for
their crappy crappy products that make
people bankrupt
i can do it for my world-saving ideas
and you know hopefully more in a
slightly
ethical way where we're doing it
together and it's an invitation so
that is what i'm doing and this last
week we tackled daniel was there we
tackled climate change and this coming
week we are tackling
drugs so
daniel would you like to give an update
introduce yourself tell us what your
project is
i guess they might not hurt so my name
is daniel
and excuse me um
i've been uh i've had a dream for doing
a project trying to
fix problems that i see in social media
and doing a social media project
that will
kind of work for the users a little bit
better
or a lot better than kind of the
the big tech what they have given us to
work with
um is i don't think it's any longer in
our interest
um especially the way that it's kind of
extra addictive
um so that's that's been the dream
that's been the plan
so um my update
is so i i got some
advice and some help from some folks and
uh the direction that i went was to try
to work with
a university uh because yeah this isn't
this is in software
and app development i can't develop an
app i was trying for a while to get a
team
of developers to basically work with
um so i found there were university
programs
where they will have students design an
app
for you as part of their senior project
it's a design project so that's the
route that i went
um i just submitted my proposal and i
should
find back i should i should find out
in what 12 days or so
if it gets accepted so i'm just keeping
my fingers crossed
and uh once mature's camera's
uh very quick one uh wikileaks is going
well
i didn't finish yesterday when i started
with database connectivity and
some internal changes and updates and
even improvements
uh my one of my experiments did not go
too well so i needed to revert and
i'm on my on my way to finish the latest
update tonight
and that's about it hyperlogos did not
move an inch forward so
it will tomorrow hopefully so that's me
right awesome i feel like i just want to
say that even if our projects don't move
forward like bentley bench
didn't work on reason score and you
didn't work on um you just said the name
and it's leaving my mind
it's like we're still working on
ourselves i mean whatever what happens
we're still bringing that to the next
piece so like we're always working on
our projects even if we're not
um i want to find out more daniel about
this university thing and how
we get our apps made through university
students
that um like what the do you still own
it at the end
uh yeah i think i read something you
said that it takes nine months to make
it which is a little
it's um yeah it's really amazing so i
found out about this through a friend of
a friend
i i don't know i'll tell you the details
i don't really know if i'm supposed to
advertise this or this is
this is not advertising i'm just telling
my story okay
i assume that there are other
universities that have a program like
this
um so this is
through university of michigan um and
i live um i live nearby
so uh what they do is
it's a it's a it's a year-long senior
project and
uh let's see they they take about
i don't know how many submissions come
in but
um they said typically
they will accept about 12 to 14
project submissions um for a year
and they said basically what they do is
um you have to give a pitch they you can
do an audio
pitch or a powerpoint presentation or
something like that
um or or a video pitch
and the students
they have some kind of autonomy with how
they decide
what project they want to work on which
i'm learning about this i mean i i
learned that that's
very good because you want them to be
excited about the topic essentially
uh the hard part was when i
was developing the app when i was
designing the app that i want to develop
kind of just with an idea phase
i basically felt like i came up with all
the solutions
i was like okay here's all the problems
that i see here's how i'm gonna address
them
um in this program you aren't really
supposed to
come up with any of the solutions i had
to change my whole pitch deck
around um because my original pitch deck
was going towards investors
or programmers that wanted to help me
out so i was like here's the problem and
here's what we're going to do about it
and they explained you don't really get
to come up with the solution
uh you only get to define the problem as
good as you can
now doesn't mean you're working you know
the students are in a vacuum
you're still working with them you i'll
see what it's like you know you may get
to prod them a little bit
but the whole first semester the whole
first fall
semester is only brainstorming
they're only doing brainstorming for the
first semester
which yeah that'll be the first four
months and then
the next semester um they're still on
on your project and then they're
actually doing the development
um you know because it's students
they're learning
they said you're going to get spaghetti
code you're not going to get the
greatest code
this is for a minimum viable product um
and i'm basically trying to get
something made that then i can show
to either potential investors
or more likely i mean i'm still gonna
need a team
at some point um i can't do this alone
so
more likely i'll have some kind of
minimal functional app
i can show off
and see what happens from there it's
i couldn't believe i was asking like so
what do i
do i you know what do i have to pay
the students um along the way
said no this is for them this is they're
going to learn
a lot um and they said
you own the entire thing at the end of
it there's some things i don't know
like does that mean it's in the app
store
or does that mean i just have a file
how is it hosted what does it mean that
i own it i i don't know
some of that stuff but
hey i didn't have a lot of other options
so
this is what i'm doing um the friend
that told me about this
said it's worked out really good
she had an app built through it
and she said she had a friend
that was like serial building apps
through this program
and she said i don't think that was
appropriate
um but hey she said like don't get too
used to this
something like that i don't know um if
you have more specific questions
throw them at me but that's the general
thing
can people from canada submit it and
when's the submission deadline
i'm wanting to have a solution raising
up and i can give them yeah so i said
like yeah this is too good to be true
um for somebody that doesn't have a cat
the capital and doesn't have a team
uh to get a minimal viable product i
think this
the deadline is the 28th
of this month um
so that's that's that
right cool i will contact you for
further information i'm going to step
out because i have a like i said a call
pretty soon
looks like you guys have this
i mean honestly i'd be curious if there
are other university programs that are
that are similar
um but i was i felt like i was
up a creek without a paddle i was i had
an idea
without a way to do anything about it
was this wasn't my first choice because
well i don't i really don't know how
much control i'll have over
what solution the students come up with
um and it's probably a good thing
in some ways because i was told because
i
explained this whole thing where i'm
like i think i already have what i want
to build
and i was told that you will be
surprised
these students are really really smart
they're gonna come up with things
you couldn't have even thought of um
and so yeah we'll see what happens
first i have to get accepted and i'm
well i'm pretty confident
but you didn't see the contract you will
sign
when you get approved
i'll i'll see the contract yeah because
i assume there will be a contract
between you and the
university so you get the cheap labor so
to speak
other junior students and
i would assume that the university is
going to have
some sort of
no not shares but um some incentive
it's not only for the students to learn
but it's also there must be something
for the university to
you know to benefit off there doesn't
have to be
but in some of the programs there is
there's there's a lot of universities
that do
in the us that will do this for free
because they just need project ideas
not a lot that i know of but i do know
of some
also that like we'll we'll work with
businesses it's usually not the first
year
and then they'll they'll take have a
business come in and have the students
work
live on projects so i hadn't heard one
do kind of an incubation like your idea
with
like like that the college is doing so
that's that's really
interesting uh it's it'll
it'll kind of be good in a way because
if you're like me you're wedded to your
idea
to your solution right but but your
passion is about solving the problem
uh also so i think it's an interesting
experiment even if you end up not using
it or something like that
to to follow that passion space
i would just double check with them make
sure that it's not
you may have already asked this question
if it's open source or not
because a lot of the students would need
to be able to use that as a portfolio
piece
um so it'd be easier for them to do it
as a portfolio piece if
it's open source but i don't know what
the college thinks about that they may
not
they may not they care about that maybe
if they can just show the photos or show
a functioning copy of it then that's
sufficient for their portfolios
but yeah i think it's a great
opportunity
yeah i was just thinking whether any of
my projects end but yeah all mine
a very specific the i the i
yeah and you may feel this way about
yours too is that the um
the interesting part is the specific
solution that i'm
experimenting with now and i don't know
because sometimes you can
state the problem in a way that
uh if you narrow it down like
instead of saying and you've already
done the pitch i'm sure so we're just
talking for other people
no well i'm i'm doing a video pitch
and i've done a couple takes oh so you
might do it and
it's not finalized i still have to
submit
i submitted a one-page paper they asked
which was basically defining the scope
like what is this going to be some huge
they're like this is within the size of
the projects we take on so that was good
um but i have to kind of sell it well
i told them the uh category
the you know it's in social media so
they're like that's fine
um but i i haven't made the final pitch
which is what the students
are going to see to say we even like
this we want to take this
on and that they understand what i'm
trying to solve yeah you're right that
if i made the
problem extremely specific
um i could guide it
more yeah cause like and i don't think
you've already mentioned that you know
you're not completely open to the
project yet
um but you mentioned that it's fighting
addiction but you could
say you know uh i want to tackle these
specific
addictive qualities so you're limiting
your kind of not limiting or narrowing
because they can always jump outside the
box but
you could say this this one
psychological effect that they're using
or these three psychological effects are
the
the problems i want to solve so as
opposed to just the broader picture of
anything addictive
which i think anything addictive would
be a more interesting thing for them but
you know you you have goals too um
so that that might be a way to to
constructively well i'll in case anyone
else does a pitch
the the way that i'm going about it and
this i have a friend who's in marketing
he said go with the story he said
what you want to do we want to explain
your current experience
and how it falls apart don't get too
technical
and he said just say this is what
happens when i use social media
and this is where it fails and he said
actually use a specific example
say and he said that's what will help
people understand one of the things i'm
worried about
and i'm going to put this the plan
currently is to put this in the pitch is
you know i'm 34 so i'm
i'm facebook came out my
freshman year of university and i've
been watching social media
evolve and change since it started and
the new apps that have come out when
from text to images to video and
whatever so i have like this big
arc of how we've used it differently
over time
and my one of my worries is that so i'm
going to mention that because
one of my worries is
the younger folks i mean they haven't
seen this evolution
so when i'm describing here's how i see
the problem
with social media currently are they
even gonna
get it are they gonna understand what
i'm seeing i don't know
yeah and that putting you know using a
personal story
and maybe a few i think if you have time
that's that's really good advice so
that's how i
support that
i think you could mention you know
afterwards i kind of looked into it and
it's this
cognitive bias of humans that you know
if you still wanted to kind of narrow it
down or think all right
you could say i wish that i could you
know
uh just have this instead of that
at near the end um
then that would kind of maybe direct it
a bit
i wish that it worked like this and then
here's the mock-ups
with this exact screen design by the way
i came up with this
but some of your main main uh
theory uh hypotheses on what's all the
issue
i think you could hit that at the end
without being too pushy
yeah well i mean i'm mostly trying to
get the i mean this is part of their
project
i don't know how big the competition is
i was suggested that they pick 12 to 14
a semester
and there were maybe about 20 or 22
submissions
so it's not bad it's not too bad i
mostly want to sell myself i said
you know you're going to be working with
me like
it's going to be fun and they said
that's part of the project too is also
you kind of participating with the
students um they spend i mean they
actually took it
surprisingly from like a business
perspective like the email
correspondence i had at the beginning
was like whoever the representative
is like essentially as if i might
already be a small startup or something
um no we need your representatives
contact information etc
i'm just going from my personal email
and all right fine
um so they had sort of a method uh
if they were talking to small business
but
uh yeah they said
what did they say uh something like
whoever your representative has to have
regular availability uh
they didn't get really specific but said
basically yeah you should be able to
return
an email within 12 hours
essentially um sounds like there will be
zoom calls
they said in the past that the
someone like me would meet up with the
students
once in a while they said it's all going
to be zoom um
but it's it sounds like it's kind of
touch and go they're teaching
the students to work as a team
the teaching them they don't want a
person
and this was from the person i talked to
that already went through the program
they don't want a micro manager they
don't want a personality type
that is um trying to
dominate and get and tell them what to
do
it's gonna be more like a check-in thing
like i'm a manager like i'm like okay
you know this week what'd you guys come
up
with something like that
um
yeah that's really good so we'll see
what happens and then my next steps
if this gets built is i mean i will
probably seek partners still
if it becomes a viable business i've
heard it's not smart to do these kinds
of things alone
um so we'll see what happens and
i don't know what else to say about my
project
you know like i'll answer questions but
um there's other folks here
um so yeah i think we just open up to
anyone that would like to be in the hot
seat has a
problem they want help solving or get an
opinion on
or share more about what's going on
pimp themselves whatever
anyone got anything ajo martish
nothing comes to mind uh it might be
interesting to talk a little bit
about that the the writing system
um if no one else
if no one has anything else
yeah that sounds interesting so let me
can i yeah hey
let me share
so this is just kind of the working
document and this system
so some of the wording that i came up
with so get your about
your idea is the like the tagline is
find value
uh and i don't know if that's already
used somewhere i haven't done any
research but that's kind of the gist
there's lots of ways to say
seek something like that um
and and actually the brand for this
isn't that important because there will
be a lot of little brands they'll be
conferrati
for the products and businesses so
wiki election for the political stuff
um so this is just like a builder for
those things
and then uh the one of the the one for
community finding is called the vibo
meter
so you can see whether this community
has a good vibe for you
uh that's really interesting that's by
chico lab
yeah uh so they're they're prototyping
that right now using miro and just kind
of having people do it manually but
if it works out and they might want to
build something else on it
so basically you can you can do a rating
system for
communities products politicians and
then dot dot because it can fit a lot of
different things
one of the uses i want to use it for is
for the no code
environment there's a lot of no code
tools and figuring out which ones
work together is very difficult and
you're often plugging together a front
end and the back end because none of the
solutions do everything and even
even if they did sometimes you have a
need that gets out of it
so having a place that you can go and
say how do these systems work together
and rate their individual features would
be good
uh so the main thing is a rating system
a review
site that's customizable uh
the people themselves can personalize
well i say personalize and categorize so
you'll be able to have a lot of control
over what you see
in the system and how you filter things
they can choose and wait all the factors
in their decisions so they
uh you know like i was saying earlier if
you're trying to pick a
a pr you know even like buying a house
which i was doing which this wouldn't be
useful for that
um but um you know being able to say
all the normal stuff you can do in in
the
the home buying stuff or in the in the
amazon except
also like in amazon you could say or
best buy or whatever
you can say i want the like if i'm
buying
cords i might say a three foot cord or
five foot cord so they have those little
check boxes on the left hand side
but then you would also have quality
features and say
you know i want something you know high
quality in the cord but i don't care
about
the ends of the cord like because i'm
going to just cut them off and use them
for something else
that's kind of a weird example and then
to be crowdsourced
which of course one of the big things we
gotta work through is how to keep it
people from gaming the system and just
filling it up with junk
so that'd be an interesting thing to
brainstorm about right now uh
evidence base this is one little ad
additional features that i want but i
don't know if anyone else would want so
if you
say this company is bad at taking care
of their employees
you could then attach an article in the
newspaper about it
uh you know a an online article from cnn
or something about it and then also
people can come in and say
maybe things that were wrong with that
article and this is
um some features that uh is also going
to be necessary
specifically in the wiki election for
the legislation for the politicians
because you may say well the politician
said this and then another person come
in and say
uh here's the full video and you can see
they took it out of contents
and he he said it is not before that cut
right
so he's actually saying the exact
opposite so having it uh evidence-based
would be good for that
so having that so that's where reason
score would fit in
i want to be low code so in theory kind
of like wordpress or some of the other
systems where you can
click a button and it would deploy a
version that then you can customize
so you could label it you could say what
the and this is asking a lot this may
not be the first version but you can say
that the entities that i that we're
rating are called politicians
and the politicians have legal so you
could name everything and talk about the
relationships and we're talking about
companies
we've got to figure out all these
relationships because it's like it who's
who owns it and then when did they own
it and then also
this company may do business with this
other company but that's not as strong
as a relationship as ownership if one of
the companies they do business
or they might just have a technical
integration with and so
they there's a relationship you want to
know about because you if you're
building these no code systems you want
to know
what systems integrate with the other
but if one of them is a bad actor
that doesn't necessarily mean the other
has any room an integration is a low
kind of a low association so also
handling that
hierarchy or not even hierarchy it's a
it's a graph
a database of all the associations and
this is a lot of features
i also got to figure out where we're
going to start
which i th which i think is just kind of
a rating system
and then adding it to where you can add
in the different things
and then i think it'll be important from
the beginning to make it multilingual
um or at least have the bones in there
to where you can turn that on without
having to do a lot of
redevelopment and i don't i haven't
had to do that a lot in my life i know
it's painful it's
maybe it's easier um anyways so that
that's kind of the the main
pitch and then i got all these details
like some use cases
i got some potential names which i
haven't researched yet
and that would just that would be just
for the builder so that name
once again isn't that important because
it's not going to be used in advertising
and then i got abstraction what are we
going to call things
entities attributes ratings you know
because you can't say politicians and
stuff
and then just open questions and then
technology wish list
and i have a technical architecture that
i would like to
yeah so i'm thinking about using
what's in here the data store mongodb
because you can
deploy that and azure um
in aws or google cloud or you can do it
locally so
um yeah so that's what i got
so if anyone has any questions or
suggestions we can add them in and then
maybe we can talk about
what features we want to put into to
make
crowdsource safe all right
so are you envisioning that this is
going to be sort of like an entire
i don't know ecosystem where it's like
got the member accounts and sort of all
these pieces
or is it more like i don't know a module
or a snap and sort of like it sounds
reason score will end up being
where you can say hey you want to be
able to score these things based
on these things you can use reason score
for any of that it sounds similar to
that but
i was thinking of making this a full
well
so i still i would like a one click full
system
where you can host your own and
customize it
i would like it to be plugable to where
if you're technical and you're like well
i don't want to use
the mongodb authentication
we can it's not that hard to get in the
code would be open source and you could
switch it over something else i want to
be flexible
um i hadn't thought it
since there's so much data coming in i
don't i couldn't
i don't think i could make it quite like
reason score where it's so
pluggable although reason score has a
lot of people coming in and out but
um so yeah one of the one of the uses
would be
potentially yeah to where you can just
kind of paste some code in there
but if you do that yeah i guess we could
do it that way as well
but i'm envisioning building it as a
whole system and then make it plugable
if people want
um but you would either have to so
reason score i always thought it'd be
like it's on someone's blog
and then if they wanted to edit reason
score they'd have to create a second
login
so for like but for for wikilection and
conferrati for reason score it'd have to
be
more it wouldn't it'd have to be more
plugged in so i guess if someone wanted
to on their blog say
here are the companies i support and
here's why
that'd be an interesting use for a plug
yeah a little widget
yeah that's sort of what was cause you
mentioned both wikileaks and confrarati
but like
in case of wiki election at least the
prototype has already started so that
you know there'll be some structure
there and it'll end up doing a lot more
than this
but this will be a very important part
of a lot of different areas
like the rating of the politicians but
then that will
be based on the rating of the
legislation and the events and
all the various things under that person
so it kind of becomes like
almost both a like a data attribute and
then a visualization tool
yeah i'm hoping to keep the code like
the main like important code abstracted
out enough
that you could use um mongodb
or you could use uh firebase which i
think
is what y'all are using so
that would also be a good test to make
sure that the central code doesn't have
any
specific technologies requirements
because we wouldn't want to move you
guys out of firebase
and i like better it's just because it's
one company
we we might do the initial prototype and
firebase then later port it to mongo
db but yeah but i hope to keep it
flexible so people can
use the the individual pieces but it
also can be deployed all together
that's a high bar but you know
right yeah because the prototype forward
collection has like
one percent of this planned right like a
very basic kind of hard-coded version
um but then in the relatively near
future that'll be one of the things that
will end up being added so that that
might be an interesting sort of
first prototype for this is like how
would the structure work and how would
that look
and it gets interesting where like you
would be rating
in this case the legislation and then
you've got how people vote
and that sort of affects what score they
get like you know if a piece of
legislation
is let's say good for the environment
well then if you vote against it it's
actually
you get that negative against you your
score
and so you're you've got like a one
level of uh of rating on the the
legislation
and then each politician has like a pool
of all the votes that they've had
so really you're visualizing the ratings
of
the legislation on the politicians yeah
right
yeah and that's why we'll have to have
the hierarchy also and similar to
products and companies you know if
a company builds a crappy product you
want that to be seen on their
company page um
so yeah that association
so good okay go ahead
would you rather talk about
evidence-based or
i i think i have a comment on evidence
based
yeah uh yeah whatever people want to
chat about
so what do you thought
well i guess i should find out what your
what you've already thought about but
uh what about the ability
for the topic being rated
uh whether that's a business a person a
product
i don't know uh to have a
rebuttal space because you could have
something that was
just raiding something down to the
ground and
the whole thing could be false um
maybe there's some kind of uh verified
like you could still have the rating
system let's just say a company
and it's getting rated
there's a spot almost like a like a
you can add a business to google maps
but like
then there's like does the company have
anything to do with the fact that this
is added to google maps like a way to
know
it's like a way for the company to come
in and say actually
you know to defend themselves uh
actually that was false information
or something like that you know you see
this on on
sites like amazon someone says hey
this product didn't work because such
and such and then
sometimes it's all true but sometimes
it's like the company's like
you didn't use the product correctly you
know and just
people can take it for what it is you
know they can say i still don't trust
the company
but if i was on a rating system uh
as any person i might want a chance to
at least give some evidence um in my
defense
yeah we should uh yeah i think that that
would be a good feature to make sure
that
well yes so first of all in the
evidence-based feature there will be the
ability for anyone to come in
and say that that evidence or that that
reasoning is wrong and put their reasons
why and that's part of the reason score
thing but like you said there's
there's still a value in in saying this
is the actual
owner of the business or the actual
politician um
so yeah i think eventually building in a
way that people can verify
their accounts which is fairly
isn't impossible it's not that hard so
um like you know you could have them
tweet out something
from from there from the official
twitter twitter account or you can have
them
just send in an email from uh
from their domain uh there's a couple
different ways but yeah i think having
uh let's see trying to think of where to
put that i don't think i want to list
that
uh right now i'll just put it up here
yes yeah so anything else about
evidence-based
so cool
so any other any other questions
suggestions concerns about this
where this is going anyway
so the most basic structure and
something that
um a user would start to build
uh the rating site from
this would be to define uh like
linguistic terms you would have nouns as
in
uh entities companies or partitions of
some things a product
and then
you would have some verbs as in this
interacts with
this so a connection relationship
between
uh two all whatever how many uh
entities and then uh this course would
be like
adjectives right something like this
so the most basic structure would um
consist of
three different types of uh information
one being the the thing you want to
write
or the relation you won't write really
because you could
in theory write right uh
both not only a
politician but if you have two
politicians and they are in
some sort of relationship uh you could
rate that as being
not very good if
yeah or some companies that do
business together and they conspire to
do something bad together
the relationship is itself can be seen
as
like monopolizing some industry
then uh yeah
yeah i have to think about that um
that's an interesting idea
so just yeah i was just trying to think
uh
how would i build a site because uh i
can compare it to the way of
thinking that is currently behind
uh the newer version of quick election
which is uh
some it's going in very similar
direction which is
uh the more entities and different types
of entities we are going to add to this
like there are already people um
um and companies
and uh relations between them
and then there is legislation and there
are
then uh relations between people
who voted for some legislation too fast
or not
there is this and there are more
entities to be added in the future
and then it only makes sense uh
for a template to exist or something
that
um does not require hardcoded
uh like this legislation module
but a module that is used to uh
instantiate uh some sort of
some type of entity and this is the
general direction
it's uh it's going towards
and yeah it's a very interesting thought
uh to cv collection as uh like
before you have a side builder you would
have a site that was
built by the specific site builder so uh
like bottom up
type of creatine structure
so it's an interesting exercise to think
about recollection as being
something that was potentially
instantiated from something
far more obstructed yeah yeah
yeah so have you gone down the path to
have instead of
so right now you do have a a people
table and a legislation table well this
would be a
entity's taste yeah and then you would
just say what type of entity each entity
is
yeah which is the way we're going yeah
it'll be important
for when we're building this to look at
the wiki election because it's the most
built one and see how compatible
we can keep it or a translation layer or
whatever because yeah you're right y'all
you've already built uh some of this
just more
uh specifically when this is gonna be
more general yeah and it would need to
be open because like
right now the idea of values they're
just columns on legislation and people
we're saying this legislation you know
here's six possible values it could
represent and then people can vote you
know plus or minus
and then you'll have the vote which just
says you're either for or against it but
there's no score there
necessarily i think there is kind of
stored but it's not interact it's just
using the legislation and then the
person is meant as like a summary of
that
which that does get to be one of the
more interesting things or in the
prototype it won't be a
a big issue but when it comes to
something like this it's like how does
the
scoring for the value actually work
because if it's just you know a sum then
you can end up with somebody with you
know a score of plus or minus
50 000 which might not be terribly
useful versus
you know if you've only got five or ten
things on file somebody might have a
score of six
which might still be somewhat meaningful
but like
is it a sum is it an average yeah and
you also need to know
like a distinction between unknown or
vague you know so really the most
technically accurate thing would be
here's here's a range between
and let's just say between zero and one
or it could be zero and a hundred
but it's between zero and one you could
have a a range say
so if it's very narrow range then you
know you have a lot of data
and if it's a wider range it's not so
we've been working on that in the debate
space
we haven't done ranges right now the
system just uh
it's kind it's mostly an average is how
we're doing it right now
um the an interesting thing about that
is that if you only have one piece of
evidence
and it's true or false it could really
throw things off right and you kind of
want to say
well this is all the information we have
and this so this is this is just
preliminary or something so it might be
a certain number of things another way
to mathematically do it i can't remember
the name of it
is that you start everyone off with one
kind of positive point one negative
point and so when you add
the third positive point it doesn't like
shoot it up to a hundred
it it shoots it up some way so that's
kind of some way that that you
you take out for when you have very
little data
but i'd like to keep kind of the math
that's another thing where i want to
kind of keep that separate so you can
decide
and maybe even write some code or
scripts to do the calculations because
that will
be something that varies quite a bit or
have several different options
right yeah like one of the interesting
pieces that isn't really being done in
the prototype
is what happens when somebody just
didn't vote for something
yeah in this case it's just sort of
saying set it to zero
but there are certain situations where
you might actually want to like minorly
affect their
score in one direction or another so it
was like we didn't vote for against it
but like
you were kind of useless in the process
so if i want somebody who's you know
like you know super pro environment or
super pro business
and you know you tend to vote present or
you tend to you know
skip that day at work uh then that might
count like
somewhat against you yeah but if you're
libertarian not voting would
probably get you a really high score
for most of the stuff anything that's
like adding to the government you just
kind of
not vote um yeah yeah figure out how to
handle that will be interesting
absenteeism yeah and that might end up
being kind of a value of the person that
values how you value values because
you're saying like right what do you
think
not voting means or voting present or
you know taking that day off work
and there are certain situations where
you have to right like if you have a
conflict
of interest you're like i have to leave
i'm yeah i i have to by law
okay that might actually be a pro or
just or or neutral
but there gets a lot of like the weird
you know
minutiae when you're down in those
details especially for the
legislation where you're going to end up
with thousands of votes on you know
thousands of pieces of legislation
yeah there's going to be a lot to chew
through yeah and i think that they'll be
kind of like a default view
because most people won't be customizing
things
uh and maybe we need to even have a
crowd-sourced way of
debating what that default view should
be because that will be very powerful
but let the people get into the to the
the weeds including that level of if the
person didn't vote
do i want to count that form against
them or neutral um
and then show the defaults and then say
you know this i would like to change
that
totally and one of the interesting
things when you open up the
the the sort of the crowdsourcing what
the values are
is choosing what values are showing by
default because if there's you know 150
different values that you could be rated
on
well i probably don't want to show all
of them
because you know some of them might not
be and i guess it might end up being
the things that you have the highest
scores in
so it might be different per person too
differentiates you from the other
politicians so maybe even if everyone
has high score of like ethics which
wouldn't happen in our government
um then maybe you just don't show that
one because everyone's the same so right
yeah and you just show the outliers well
you vary from the norm
would be interesting um yeah
or i mean the main thing is there might
be i don't know there might be an
overall score although i guess maybe not
um and then we have to kind of figure
out for some of these
you know the funding model will be the
information
so how much do you allow without coming
in and creating an account
how much work do you make the person go
through when they create an account
another thing is should people should
there be a bounty system
to where people can get paid for doing
investigations
so like if i want to buy a new no code
platform and like two or three platforms
came online and no one's used them yet
maybe i can through the system say hey
crowdsource
the funding or use another external
system and just link to it
like there's uh anyways but where
you could advertise it if anyone else
wants to
have someone go in and review these
three systems then we pay them for this
and the data gets added to the
collective
yeah yeah
um i don't know if y'all have answered
this yet
but um so it sounds like
kind of like wordpress i could i could
take
this uh platform
a framework essentially and i could
create my own and i could be like i want
to make the site for
raiding video games right and
hopefully i gain traction or maybe i
make it private
because i just want to do it a lot
amongst my 12
friends yeah and we want to have our own
thing or i can make it more public and
you know have 50 000 users or something
right
is is that an accurate assessment yeah
okay exactly
so one of the things that comes to mind
is
will you have um like
common i don't know how to put this like
common rating tokens like
because you could have different
ecosystems say let's just say video
games
and by the way i love the idea of
raiding the relationship
um but so i've got maybe i've got like
video games
and companies and video game characters
like as
different things in in my system
uh and if i make my new
site do i have to start from scratch
or maybe i want to start from scratch i
want to have
you know dan's rating site or something
because i've got a different
viewpoint but maybe i don't want to do
all the work on the companies i just
want to rate the video games but i still
want to show the relationship
can i import or can i link to
a master token of
companies and so i
you know like a map i don't know how to
put a master wiki or something
um it's almost like sharing data between
two of
similar apps
is this turning into blockchain yeah i
mean that sort of came to mind
and it's like i can create my own token
or something
and be like no i want you yeah i want to
use dan's
you know his ecosystem rating system
because i trust him and his friends or
maybe they're all whatever tech people
or i want to use like the imdb
um system for the characters or
something
like and which where do i want to pull
from
and some will win and some will lose out
as it evolves over time
uh have you thought about that no the
only thing we thought about so far is
that
for both the politicians one and the
products one they'll both have companies
um because you'll you'll want to say
this company is lobbying this politician
um so it would be interesting to have
them
share the company database which we
talked about just doing it all in the
same system and having different views
um i so i would see that as an advanced
possible feature if enough people kind
of wanted it
of course it's always open source code
so you can
literally pull the database and put it
in there and write your own
code that would keep them in sync or
something or
yeah so i hadn't thought that far down
the path
yeah it's pretty high it's pretty high
level but i thought
yeah if i was comparing all these things
in these three different video game
categories
maybe i want to automatically import the
data for companies and characters
but me and my friends want to have our
own ratings on the games and so
how could that be decentralized
you'd have almost have almost like
different tokens
uh and maybe i want to pull from the
biggest one
or i like this alternate one uh better
yeah yeah that's that's interesting
one day uh a little bit
and uh it's that it would be nice to
have not only open source but
open source code but on also open data
which is uh we are going to put
lots of effort into building a database
of
politicians and companies anyway and
then
it would be nice to be able to
do some kind of subscript subscription
or just
open the data of some part of the data
so
rating
sites built by our users would be able
to use the shared data
and have this like established
foundation of
data that has been vetted enough and
it's
considered like true enough
and common enough
so people can share and use it for their
own ratings if they want for example to
build
uh and uh
yeah if someone wanted to have uh
something
similar similar to weak election but uh
focusing on different aspects then the
data
itself the static data of parties and
politicians and
companies would be just there but
someone could
do their own view and their own like
the window to the data and presented in
slightly different way
i'll present it's like from slightly
different different
angle oh yeah i think that could be
without that
it'll end up being fairly control like i
think there will be open
but it'll be sort of all possibly like a
control that you would use so any
filters you put anything that like any
spin that you're putting on
on the data is plainly plain visible
so if you're saying well look at how the
data looks if you completely ignore all
this evidence
you might be able to do that but that's
plainly visible when you're looking at
the data like oh here's the person's
score if you completely ignore
everything that happened over the last
five years
oh that's a weird filter to use why
would you do that
um but i think an example of what you
might be talking about is possibly
because there's also going to be
trackers like it's more a people tracker
as opposed to just politicians
so an example might be like an expert or
a journalist
and so the end goal is hopefully
eventually
like new sites or even facebook would
have some sort of an integration that
would say like if you're talking about
you know a news story the person that
wrote it might have a profile so you can
sort of see
a summary on where that person's
allegiances might lie
and previous things they've written and
sort of what values they have
but then also each person discussed in
in the article if they're talking about
a politician a a way for there to
probably just be like a side panel
saying you know people in this article
and then like a summary of all the
people talked about so
you don't have to go to wikilection to
see it but you're able to use that data
elsewhere i think we're running out of
time so we might go ahead and close it
off that i really appreciate everyone's
feedback and participation
yes yeah good one
i haven't seen a ravage no uh any
closing comments
nope
i was going to say that ultimately uh
given enough
different rating systems and enough
people looking at
the shared data what would be possible
in theory is discovering
new connections and correlations between
different aspects of
possibly far away uh
like data right new knowledge is going
to be discovered
yes i just brought up one of the things
that one great thing about doing this in
game b
is especially for products and
politicians is you can use the data to
find
gaps in them in the area in where
we can be very effective in how we
share yeah which kind of ties into
yesterday's conversation
yeah if you get into organizations and
products and even into these of
these supply chains you can start to say
like oh look there's no product here or
oh we are there's only one offering for
this supply chain that uses slave labor
but i talked to an expert that said you
could pretty easily not do that
like yeah to find the caps that's an
interesting point
well i had a final thought uh which was
you know um when i was thinking about
having uh like a central
database you know here's the standard
rating or you could like make your own
for you and your friends or something
you know i just thought you know that
might work okay for something like video
games or
whatever but you know it
there might be things you might not want
to allow that for
like politicians could be a good example
where it's like
well there isn't a standard rating
and now it's like i don't know which to
go to do i go to the
right wing rating you know and their
opinion or the left-wing one you know
um so it's kind of
it's tricky i think it almost depends on
what the
topic is whether you'd want you know how
serious how important is it i mean if
we're rating companies on their
eco viability um we may want
one uh token to look for
for a company
just a final thought yeah but to figure
that out
alrighty goodbye facebook and youtube
all right